tanvi mehta

What do you get when you mix a visual designer, human interest, and painstaking meticulousness?

A design practitioner who thoughtfully creates experiences through visuals.

Through my work in visual design, I explore the impact of visual cues on human behaviour, and by extension, user experience. An eye for detail, design research and scrupulous planning are strengths I bring to the table, along with a big heart and lots of tea sachets.

Phone Number: +1 646 515 5795

Email Address: tanvimehta6697@gmail.com

Website: www.inkyesthetics.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/

tanvi-mehta-inkyesthetics/

Instagram Account: @inkyesthetics

Technical Skills

User Research, User Strategy, Wireframing, User testing, Prototyping, UI design, User Centred Design, Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign, Flash, Fireworks, Adobe XD, InVision, Sketch, Figma, Interaction Design, Usability Testing, User, Rapid Prototyping, Visual Design, Branding & Packaging.

Soft Skills:

- Great communication skills, ability to pitch.
- Has experience and is capable of giving design directions to the team, as well as able to do hands on work.
- Interest in technology and how it can enable new possibilities.
- Capable of finding and organizing issues, and provide the solutions.
- Excellent written, design and verbal communication skills
- Professional experience of Branding, User Experience and Adverstising.
- The ability to multi-task and handle changing priorities.
- Experience in collaborative teamwork.
- Ability to research and uncover insights and gage new opportunities to create impactful systems.
- Excellent at observing with a curiousity to understand behaviours.

Certificates:

Aspen Institute Design Sprint December 2022

Visual Elements of User Interface Design California Institute of the Arts// June 2020

Design Hackathon 2020 Winjit Technologies Pvt Ltd// July 2020

Education:

Parsons School of Design | The New School // New York, United States of America // 2021 - Present

Currently pursuing Master of Science in Strategic Design and Management Recipient: Dean's Merit based scholarship

Srishti Institute of Art Design and Technology // Bangalore, India // 2015 - 2019

Secured a Bachelor of Design in Visual Communication and Strategic Branding.

Experience:

The Glitch, Flux // Visual Designer

Mumbai, India

March 2020 - June 2021

The Glitch, W.P.P is India's leading creative agency headquartered in Mumbai, with offices in Delhi and Bangalore.

- Worked on campaign ideas, strategize and build visual style guides for brands such as Netflix, Dell, One Plus, BoAt, Cred, Moms and Co, Diageo, etc.
- Led the design team international campaign for Dell during the pandemic. Collaborated with various teams across the agency and communicated with the client at different points during the course of the project. Was awarded 'Employee of the Month' twice during the course of this project.
- Researched, strategized, and designed graphics for various advertising videos for Instagram TV, YouTube, and LinkedIn for brands such as Netflix, Dell, BoAt, Moms and Co, Diageo, etc.
- Ideated and designed campaign mockups on pitches for brands such as Cred, Pepsi, Bumble, Pepperfry, etc. The agency was able to get on board brands like Cred, Pepsi, Bumble as permanent

Hepta // UX/UI Designer & Brand Visualiser

Mumbai, India

August 2019 - February 2020

The Hepta is a UI/UX and Technology agency, serving startups and businesses to achieve strategic objectives by delivering impactful UI/UX and technology services.

- Ideated and designed e-commerce and charity websites mockups on Photoshop with a cross-functional team inclusive of stakeholders, project managers and developers to create responsive interfaces and a user-centered experience.
- Collaborated with teams of developers, user interface, and user experience designers.
- Curated logos, brand guidelines, and packaging designs to help upcoming brands gain recognition.

Rivet Design Studio // User Experience (UX) Design Intern

Bangalore, India

April 2019 - July 2019

Rivet Design is a communication and design studio, which works on environmental graphics, brand experience design and various ways of communication through design.

Worked from ideation to execution and designed the environmental experience design for the Amazon Campus in Hyderabad.

Yes Yes Why Not // User Experience (UX) and User Interface (UI) Design Intern Mumbai, India // April 2018 - July 2018

Barworld India // Illustrator & Graphic Designer Freelancer Mumbai, India // May 2017 - June 2021

Zcyphher Studio // Graphic Design Intern Mumbai, India // May 2016 - July 2016

Cat Café Studio // Graphic Design Intern Mumbai, India // May 2016 - July 2016

Projects:

Fusion // Currently working on 'Fusion' in Parsons School of Design. Fusion is an application that helps creative professionals have a creatic flow, gain inspiration create conversation and interact with other creatives in spaces around you while working in a hybrid/remotely setting.

- Conducted primary and secondary research, synthesised information and insight generation, as well as executed early ideation analysis, prototyping, testing and final product.
- Worked on the Business Model Cavas for this application.
- Technologies used: Miro, Mural, Figma, Adobe Illustrator.

Creative Collaborations // Worked in a 'Creative Collaboration' project in Kutch with a Rabari artisan and built a system to bridge the communication gap between her and the target audience by using storytelling.

- Performed primary and secondary research, conducted field experiments and insight generation. executed early ideation and market analysis, prototyping, and customer feedback for creating a tool to reduce the communication gap between the artisan and her audience.
- Workd on a Business Model Canvas for this system.
- Technologies used: Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop and InDesign